#### Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/franzrumstadt (LinkedIn)

### Top-Kenntnisse

Corporate Communications
Marketing
Pricing Strategy

### Languages

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual) Englisch (Full Professional) Französisch (Elementary) Latein (Elementary)

### Honors-Awards

Scholarship German National Academic Foundation

## Franz Rumstadt

Project Manager Communication Strategy at Porsche | #30u30 2021 PR Report | PhD Candidate at HHL

Stuttgart

## Zusammenfassung

Project Manager Communication Strategy and Reputation at Porsche with a practical background in the German Automotive Industry allowing for experiences with global players such as Porsche, Daimler or Oliver Wyman. PhD Candidate at HHL Leipzig focusing on CEO Activism research. Holding a MSc with Distinction from Imperial College Business School, London. Graduated from Mannheim Business School including a term abroad at Warwick Business School, UK. Founder, former national chairman and president of the German Student Automotive Association. Bavarian Swabian by choice.

## Berufserfahrung

Porsche AG
3 Jahre 9 Monate

Project Manager Communication Strategy and Reputation Oktober 2021 - Present (6 Monate)

Region Stuttgart

Executive Assistant to Vice President Communications, Sustainability and Politics

Juli 2018 - Oktober 2021 (3 Jahre 4 Monate)

Stuttgart und Umgebung, Deutschland

Oliver Wyman Consulting Intern Juli 2017 - September 2017 (3 Monate) München und Umgebung, Deutschland

**Automotive Strategic Management Consulting** 

Data driven sales optimisation for a German OEM

Data-analyses and presentation of according results

Management of meeting preparation and team-summaries

Daimler AG
Intern
Juni 2017 - Juli 2017 (2 Monate)
Stuttgart und Umgebung, Deutschland

Big Data/After Sales - Mercedes me

Data-analyses and insight-presentations

Case study preparation

Trend-scouting and innovation process development

Universität Mannheim 1 Jahr 4 Monate

Student Research Assistant Chair of Business-to-Business-Marketing, Sales & Pricing

Januar 2016 - Dezember 2016 (1 Jahr)

Mannheim und Umgebung, Deutschland

Student Research Assistant at the Chair of Business-to-Business-Marketing, Sales & Pricing, Prof. Dr. Dr. h.c. mult. Christian Homburg

Assistance in new publications
Research
Text-Editing

Student Tutor Chair of Strategic and International Management September 2015 - Januar 2016 (5 Monate)

Mannheim und Umgebung, Deutschland

Module-tutorial "Strategic and International Management"

Subject-oriented modules and presentations
Preparation of class-materials
Academic support for the chair's teaching team

Dr. h.c. Ing. F. Porsche AG
Intern
Juni 2016 - Oktober 2016 (5 Monate)
Zuffenhausen

Public Relations - Corporate Publishing

Strategic projects in the department of corporate communications

Content Management in internal and external platforms

Support for Online-/Social Media-Communication

Page 2 of 4

# German Federal Parliament - Deutscher Bundestag Intern

Juni 2015 - Juli 2015 (2 Monate)

Berlin

Office intern for Dr. Astrid Freudenstein, MdB (Member of the parliament)

Web-administration and content-creation Journalistic relations and media coverage Event and topic-reporting

https://www.astrid-freudenstein.de/themenfuelle-im-praktikum/

### Oskar Dilo Maschinenfabrik KG

Intern

Januar 2015 - Februar 2015 (2 Monate)

Eberbach am Neckar

Controlling intern at Dilo (world market leader for textile/non-woven engineering)

Self dependent project-optimisation of E-Invoicing processes

Implementation concept for E-Invoicing processes and policies across the group

Support in the departments for Controlling, Financial and Cost Accounting

Daimler AG Student Intern Mai 2012 - Juni 2012 (2 Monate)

HR Intern at Daimler AG/Daimler Financial Services

Creation of job postings and job profiles Support in HR complexity management Support in HR Controlling

## Ausbildung

HHL Leipzig Graduate School of Management

PhD Candidate in Strategic Management · (Dezember 2020)

### Imperial College Business School

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Strategic Marketing · (2017 - 2018)

### Universität Mannheim

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Betriebswirtschaftslehre (Business Administration) · (2014 - 2017)

### University of Warwick

Semester Abroad, Business Administration · (2016 - 2016)

Albertus-Magnus-Gymnasium, Regensburg

Abitur · (2006 - 2014)